= 权力的游戏 第1季第6集 =
黄金王冠
首播时间: 2011年5月22日
== 翻译: freesand ==
(君临城)
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
(鹰巢城)
(临冬城)
(绝境长城)
(维斯多斯拉克)
原著: 乔治马丁
Game of Thrones 1x06
A Golden Crown
Original Air Date on May 22, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
请原谅, 陛下.
Your pardon, Your Grace.
我应当起身, 但...
I would rise, but...
你知道你夫人做了什么吗?
Do you know what your wife has done?
她所做的都是遵照我的命令.
She did nothing I did not command.
谁能想到她会那样做?
Who'd have thought she had it in her?
你凭什么对我的家人下手?
By what right dare you lay hands on my blood?
我是国王之手, 负责维护和平...
I am the King's Hand, charged with keeping the peace...
你曾是国王之手.
You were the King's Hand.
你现在是待罪之身.
You shall now be held accountable.
你们两个能不能都住口?!
Oh, will both of you shut your mouths?!
凯特林必须释放提利昂, 你要与詹姆和好.
Catelyn will release Tyrion and you'll make your peace with Jaime.
他屠杀了我的部下...
He butchered my men...
当时史塔克大人喝醉了酒
Lord Stark was returning drunk
刚从妓院里出来, 他的手下攻击了詹姆.
from a brothel when his men attacked Jaime.
- 安静, 臭女人. - 詹姆逃出城去了.
- Quiet, woman. - Jaime has fled the city.
请允许我把他抓回来接受审判.
Give me leave to bring him back to justice.
我当你是一国之君.
I took you for a King.
- 你闭嘴. - 他攻击了
- Hold your tongue. - He's attacked
我的一个兄弟又绑架了另一个.
one of my brothers and abducted the other.
我才该穿铠甲, 你应该穿裙子当女人.
I should wear the armor and you the gown.
我会把这当作荣誉奖章.
I shall wear this like a badge of honor.
那就给我安静地戴好, 否则我让你更光荣.
Wear it in silence or I'll honor you again.
看到她是如何待我的了?
See what she does to me?
我亲爱的妻子.
My loving wife.
我不该打她的.
I should not have hit her.
这实在不是...
That was not...
实在不是国王该有的举动.
That was not Kingly.
如果我们不采取措施,
If we don't act,
将会爆发一场战争.
there will be a war.
那就叫你夫人放那个小恶魔...
So tell your wife to return that little shit of an Imp
回君临.
to King's Landing.
她已经玩够了, 别再继续了.
She's had her fun, now put an end to it.
你听到没有? 送只渡鸦去解决这件事.
You hear me? Send a raven and put an end to it.
那么詹姆兰尼斯特怎么处理?
And what about Jaime Lannister?
- 詹姆怎么处理? - 我几乎把半个王国
- What about Jaime? - I'm half a Kingdom in debt
都抵押给了他那该死的老爸.
to his bloody father.
我不知道你和那帮黄头发的混蛋有什么过节.
I don't know what happened between you and those yellow-haired shits.
我也不想知道. 关键的问题是...
I don't want to know. This is what matters...
我将无法维持对七国的统治
I can't rule the Kingdoms
如果史塔克家和兰尼斯特家打成一团.
if the Starks and the Lannisters are at each other's throats.
所以到此为止吧.
So enough.
遵命, 陛下.
As you command, Your Grace.
如果您允许,
With your leave,
我会返回临冬城处理此事.
I will return to Winterfell and set matters straight.
不行. 送只渡鸦去吧.
Piss on that. Send a raven.
我要你留下来.
I want you to stay.
我是国王. 我说什么就是什么.
I'm the King. I get what I want.
我没喜欢过我的亲兄弟们.
I never loved my brothers.
这很令人伤心, 但事实如此.
A sad thing for a man to admit, but it's true.
你才是我的兄弟.
You were the brother I chose.
等我打猎回来再谈吧.
We'll talk when I return from the hunt.
打猎?
The hunt?
打猎能令我头脑清爽.
Killing things clears my head.
我不在时你必须代我坐那把铁骑子.
You'll have to sit on the throne while I'm away.
你一定会比我更讨厌它.
You'll hate it more than I do.
坦格利安家那女孩...
The Targaryen girl...
七层地狱啊, 不要再提她了.
seven hells, don't start with her again.
那女孩必须死, 我不想再谈这件事.
The girl will die and I'll hear no more of it.
把徽章戴上. 要是你再把它摘下来,
Put on the badge. And if you ever take it off again,
我向圣母发誓我会把这烂东西给詹姆兰尼斯特.
I swear to the mother I'll pin the damned thing on Jaime Lannister.
卡丽煕?
Khaleesi?
哦, 卡丽煕!
Oh, Khaleesi!
你受伤了.
You're hurt.
- 别太快了. - 快点, 小舞.
- Not too fast. - Come on, Dancer.
你准备何时告诉他?
When are you gonna tell him?
现在不行.
Not now.
- 血债血还. - 快点!
- Blood for blood. - Bran: Come on!
你必须让兰尼斯特家为乔里他们的死付出代价.
You need to make the Lannisters pay for Jory and the others.
- 你是在谈论战争. - 我是在谈论正义.
- Robb: You're talking about war. - I'm talking about justice.
只有临冬城主
Only the Lord of Winterfell
才能召集封臣出动军队.
can call in the bannermen and raise an army.
兰尼斯特家的人用矛刺伤了你父亲的腿.
A Lannister put his spear through your father's leg.
弑君者跑回凯岩城去避风头了...
The Kingslayer rides for Casterly Rock where no one can touch him...
你要我进攻凯岩城吗?
you want me to march on Casterly Rock?
- 你不是小孩子了. - 快点.
- You're not a boy anymore. - Bran: Come on.
他们攻击你父亲. 他们已经挑起战争了.
They attacked your father. They've already started the war.
你父亲不在时, 你要负责代表你的家族.
It's your duty to represent your House when your father can't.
而不用你来负责, 因为不是你的家族.
And it's not your duty, because it's not your House.
布兰去哪儿了?
Where's Bran?
我不知道. 又不是我的家族.
I don't know. It's not my House.
罗柏?
Robb?
孤身一人在幽暗的树林里.
All alone in the deep, dark woods.
我不是一个人. 我和我哥哥在一起.
I'm not alone. My brother is with me.
我可没看见他.
I don't see him.
你把他藏在斗篷下面了?
Got him hidden under your cloak?
哦, 真是个漂亮的别针.
Ooh, that's a pretty pin.
- 是银子的. - 我们要那别针
- Silver. - We'll take the pin
还有这匹马. 下来.
and the horse. Get down.
快一点.
Be quick about it.
我下不来.
I can't.
这马鞍... 这皮带.
The saddle... the straps.
你有什么毛病? 你是残废?
What's wrong with you? You some kind of cripple?
我是临冬城的布兰登史塔克.
I'm Brandon Stark of Winterfell.
要是再不放手, 我会让你们通通没命!
If you don't let me be, I'll have you all killed!
把他的小鸡鸡割下来塞他嘴里.
Cut his little cock off and stuff it in his mouth.
这孩子死了就不值钱啦.
The boy's worth nothing dead.
班扬史塔克的亲属?
Benjen Stark's own blood?
想想看曼斯会怎么奖励我们.
Think what Mance would give us.
曼斯雷德和北境通通见鬼去吧.
Piss on Mance Rayder and piss on the North.
我们要去南方, 越远越好.
We're going as far South as South goes.
多恩那里不会有异鬼.
There ain't no White Walkers down in Dorne.
放下刀子!
Drop the knife!
放开他, 我会给你们留条活路.
Let him go and I'll let you live.
罗柏.
Robb.
- 罗柏. - 闭嘴.
- Robb. - Shut up.
把剑扔了!
Drop the blade!
- 不, 不要. - 快点.
- No, don't. - Do it.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
是的. 一点也不痛.
Yes. It doesn't hurt.
坚强的小伙子.
Tough little lad.
在铁群岛, 你必须杀死过一个敌人才算成人.
In the Iron Islands, you're not a man until you've killed your first enemy.
干得好.
Well done.
你发疯了吗?
Have you lost your mind?
要是你没射中怎么办?
What if you'd missed?
他会杀掉你再割断布兰的喉咙.
He would have killed you and cut Bran's throat.
- 你没权利... - 没权利做什么, 救你兄弟的命?
- You don't have the right... - To what, to save your brother's life?
这是唯一选择, 所以我做了.
It was the only thing to do, so I did it.
她怎么处理?
What about her?
饶我一命, 大人, 我是您的人了.
Give me my life, My Lord, and I'm yours.
饶她一命吧.
We'll keep her alive.
莫德!
Mord!
开门! 莫德!
Turnkey! Mord!
莫德!
Mord!
小矮人真吵闹!
Dwarf man making noise!
你想不想发财?
How would you like to be rich?
小矮人还在吵闹.
Dwarf man still making noise.
我的家族很富有.
My family is rich.
我们有金子, 很多金子.
We have gold, lots of gold.
我打算给你很多很多金子...
I'm prepared to give you lots of gold in...
没有金子!
No gold!
嗯, 我身上没有.
Well, I don't have it here.
没有金子.
No gold.
混帐.
Fuck off.
我今天不想练习.
I don't want to practice today.
不想?
No?
他们杀了乔里.
They killed Jory.
我父亲也受伤了.
My father is hurt.
我不想再练这愚蠢的木剑了.
I don't care about stupid wooden swords.
你有烦恼了.
You are troubled.
- 是的. - 很好!
- Yes. - Good!
烦恼的时候最适合练习.
Trouble is the perfect time for training.
当你在草地上与玩偶和猫咪一起跳舞,
When you are dancing in the meadow with your dolls and kittens,
那可不是适合练习打斗的时候.
this is not when fighting happens.
我不喜欢玩偶和...
I don't like dolls and k...
你心不在焉.
You're not here.
你在烦恼.
You're with your trouble.
如果在打斗时你还在烦恼...
If you are with your trouble when fighting happens...
...你会有更大的麻烦.
...More trouble for you.
就是这样.
Just so.
你如何能迅如蛇...
How can you be quick as a snake...
...或者静如影...
...Or as quiet as a shadow...
...如果你心不在焉?
...When you are somewhere else?
你在担心你的父亲, 嗯?
You are fearing for your father, hmm?
那是对的.
That is right.
- 你有向诸神祈祷吗? - 旧神和新神.
- Do you pray to the gods? - The old and the new.
只有一个神
There is only one God
那就是死神.
and his name is Death.
我们向死神只说一句话:
And there is only one thing we say to Death:
"今天不行."
"Not today."
(男孩! 男孩! 强壮的男孩!
Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
- (王子骑着马!) - (男孩! 男孩! 强壮的男孩!)
- Priestess: Khalakka Dothrae! - Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
- (男孩! 男孩! 强壮的男孩!) - 王子骑着马!
- Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj! - Khalakka Dothrae!
她必须吃掉那一整颗心吗?
She has to eat the whole heart?
我希望那不是我的马.
I hope that wasn't my horse.
她做得很好.
She's doing well.
她吃不下的.
She'll never keep it down.
(男孩! 男孩! 强壮的男孩!)
Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
(王子骑着马!)
Khalakka Dothrae!
告诉我她在说什么.
Tell me what she's saying.
"王子骑着马.
"The prince is riding.
我听见他的蹄声隆隆.
I have heard the thunder of his hooves.
他的马迅捷如风.
Swift as the wind he rides.
他的敌人将在他面前颤抖...
His enemies will cower before him...
敌人的妻子们将悲伤泣血."
And their wives will weep tears of blood."
她将生下一个男孩.
She's going to have a boy.
他不会是一个真正的坦格利安.
He won't be a real Targaryen.
他不会是一条真龙.
He won't be a true Dragon.
(骑着世界的骏马!)
Vezh fin saja rhaesheseres!
"骑着世界的骏马."
"The stallion who mounts the world."
那骏马将是卡奥中的卡奥.
The stallion is the Khal of Khals.
他将统一所有的卡拉萨.
He shall unite the people into a single Khalasar.
全世界的人都将属于他.
All the people of the world will be his herd.
(...骑着世界!)
...Rhaesheseres!
(骑着世界!)
Rhaesheseres!
(王子在我体内骑马!)
(他的名字叫做雷戈!)
雷戈! 雷戈!
Rhaego! Rhaego!
雷戈! 雷戈...
Rhaego! Rhaego...
他们爱戴她.
They love her.
雷戈! 雷戈!
Rhaego! Rhaego!
雷戈! 雷戈...
Rhaego! Rhaego...
今天她是一位真正的王后了.
She truly is a queen today.
别让他们看到你在维斯多斯拉克带着剑.
Don't let them see you carrying a sword in Vaes Dothrak.
你知道这违反律法.
You know the law.
这律法管不着我.
It's not my law.
它们不是属于你的.
They don't belong to you.
她的东西都是属于我的.
Whatever is hers is also mine.
或许曾经属于你.
Once, perhaps.
如果我卖掉一颗龙蛋, 就足够买一条船.
If I sell one egg, I'll have enough to buy a ship.
卖两颗... 一条船加一支军队.
Two eggs... a ship and an army.
- 你拿了三颗. - 我需要一支大军.
- And you have all three. - I need a large army.
我是一个王朝复兴最后的希望, 莫尔蒙.
I'm the last hope of a dynasty, Mormont.
世界上古往今来最伟大的王朝
The greatest dynasty this world has ever seen
自五岁起我就担负着这项使命...
on my shoulders since I was five years old...
却从没人给予我在那帐篷里他们所给予她的东西.
and no one has ever given me what they gave to her in that tent.
从来没有.
Never.
一点也没有.
Not a piece of it.
没有这些我如何能履行我的使命?
How can I carry what I need to carry without it?
嗯?
Hmm?
没有财富或恐惧或爱戴如何能进行统治?
Who can rule without wealth or fear or love?
哦, 你站在那里, 又高贵又荣誉.
Oh, you stand there, all nobility and honor.
你以为我没发现你是用何种眼神看着我的妹妹, 嗯?
You don't think I see you looking at my little sister, hmm?
你以为我不知道你想要什么?
Don't think I know what you want?
我无所谓. 你可以拥有她.
I don't care. You can have her.
她可以当蛮子的王后并且尽情...
She can be Queen of the savages and dine
享用那最美味的马的器官,
on the finest bloody horseparts,
你也可以尽情享用她的任何器官.
and you can dine on whichever parts of her you like.
让我走吧.
But let me go.
你可以走.
You can go.
但你不能带走龙蛋.
You can't have the eggs.
你曾向我宣誓效忠.
You swore an oath to me.
忠诚对你来说不值一提吗?
Does loyalty mean nothing to you?
那是我的一切.
It means everything to me.
然而你还是站在这里.
And yet here you stand.
所以我还是站在这里.
And yet here I stand.
莫德!
Mord!
莫德.
Mord.
又在吵闹了!
Noise again!
- 有关那些金子... - 没有金子!
- About the gold... - No gold!
- 没有金子. - 听我说!
- No gold. - Listen to me!
听我说.
Listen to me.
有时候财产
Sometimes possession
是个抽象的概念...
is an abstract concept...
他们抓我的时候拿走了我的钱包,
When they captured me, they took my purse,
但那些金子还是我的.
but the gold is still mine.
在哪儿?
Where?
在哪儿? 我不知道在哪儿,
Where? I don't know where,
但等他们给我自由的时候...
but when they free me...
你想要自由?
You want free?
那儿有自由.
Go be free.
你有没有听说过这句话
Have you ever heard the phrase
"象兰尼斯特家一样有钱"?
"rich as a Lannister"?
你当然听说过!
Of course you have!
你是个聪明人.
You're a smart man.
你知道兰尼斯特家.
You know who the Lannisters are.
我就是兰尼斯特家的.
I am a Lannister.
泰温之子提利昂!
Tyrion, son of Tywin!
而且, 你当然也听说过这句话,
And of course, you have also heard the phrase,
"兰尼斯特有债必还."
"a Lannister always pays his debts."
如果你替我传个口信...
If you deliver a message from me...
给艾林夫人, 就算我欠你一笔债.
to Lady Arryn, I will be in your debt.
我会给你很多金子.
I will owe you gold.
如果你传了口信
If you deliver the message
如果我活下来了, 我一定会的.
and I live, which I very much intend to do.
什么口信?
What message?
告诉她我打算认罪.
Tell her I wish to confess my crimes.
你打算认罪?
You wish to confess your crimes?
是的, 夫人.
Yes, My Lady.
我愿意, 夫人.
I do, My Lady.
天牢可以让任何人屈服.
The sky cells always break them.
说吧, 小恶魔.
Speak, Imp.
坦诚地面对诸神吧.
Meet your gods as an honest man.
该从何说起呢, 各位大人和夫人?
Where do I begin, my lords and ladies?
我是个坏蛋,
I'm a vile man,
我承认这一点.
I confess it.
我犯下的罪过数不胜数.
My crimes and sins are beyond counting.
我撒过谎骗过人...
I have lied and cheated...
赌过钱嫖过妓.
gambled and whored.
我不是特别擅长暴力,
I'm not particularly good at violence,
但我擅长鼓动他人替我施暴.
but I'm good at convincing others to do violence for me.
我想你是想听具体一点的.
You want specifics, I suppose.
七岁那年, 我看见一个女仆
When I was seven I saw a servant girl
在河里洗澡.
bathing in the river.
我偷走了她的衣服.
I stole her robe.
于是她不得不...
She was forced to return to the castle
光着身子哭着回城堡.
naked and in tears.
如果我闭上眼睛,
If I close my eyes,
还能看见她跳动的乳头.
I can still see her tits bouncing.
十岁那年, 我在我叔叔的靴子里塞满羊粪.
When I was 10 I stuffed my Uncle's boots with goatshit.
别人问我的时候,
When confronted with my crime,
我归咎于一个侍从. 那可怜孩子挨了鞭打
I blamed a squire. Poor boy was flogged
而我却逃脱了惩罚.
and I escaped justice.
十二岁那年
When I was 12
我朝一锅炖海龟猛挤我那小鳗鱼...
I milked my eel into a pot of turtle stew.
猛扭我那小独眼蛇...
I flogged the one-eyed snake.
猛搓我那小香肠...
I skinned my sausage.
猛揍我那爱哭的小秃子...
I made the bald man cry
给那炖海龟加了点作料,
into the turtle stew,
我相信我老姐把它吃了.
which I do believe my sister ate.
至少我希望她吃了.
At least I hope she did.
有一回我又带了一头公驴和一个蜂窝
Once I brought a jackass and a honeycomb
- 去一家妓院... - 住口!
- into a brothel... - Silence!
后来怎么样了?
What happened next?
你以为你在干什么?
What do you think you're doing?
我在认罪啊.
Confessing my crimes.
提利昂大人, 你被控
Lord Tyrion, you are accused
雇人行刺我卧病在床的儿子布兰,
of hiring a man to slay my son Bran in his bed,
以及密谋害死我妹妹的丈夫
and of conspiring to murder my sister's husband
琼恩艾林大人, 国王之手.
Lord Jon Arryn, the Hand of the King.
哦, 我非常抱歉.
Oh, I'm very sorry.
我对这些一无所知.
I don't know anything about all that.
你的玩笑开够了.
You've had your little joke.
我相信你玩得很愉快.
I trust you enjoyed it.
莫德, 带他回地牢.
Mord, take him back to the dungeon.
这次找个更小的房间...
But this time find a smaller cell...
而且地板也更斜的.
With a steeper floor.
难道这就是所谓
Is this how justice
艾林谷的正义?
is done in the Vale?
你指控我有罪,
You accuse me of crimes,
我否认有罪, 所以你把我扔进牢房
I deny them, so you throw me into a cell
冻饿而死?
to freeze and starve?
国王的正义到哪里去了?
Where is the King's Justice?
既然我遭到指控, 我要求公平审判!
I am accused and demand a trial!
如果你被判有罪,
If you're tried and found guilty,
那么依照国王的律法你只有死路一条.
then by the King's own laws you will pay with your life.
我尊重律法.
I understand the law.
我们鹰巢城没有刽子手.
We have no executioner in the Eyrie.
我们这里有更文雅的法子.
Life is more elegant here.
打开月门.
Open the moon door.
你想要一场审判, 兰尼斯特大人.
You want a trial, My Lord Lannister.
很好.
Very well.
我儿子会倾听你要说的话,
My son will listen to whatever you have to say,
而你将接受他的判决.
and you will hear his judgment.
然后你就可以离开...
Then you will leave...
从这道门或那道门.
By one door or the other.
不必惊动罗宾大人了.
No need to bother Lord Robin.
我要求比武审判.
I demand a trial by combat.
你当然有这个权利.
You have that right.
夫人, 我请您恩准.
My Lady, I beg the honor.
让我做您的代理骑士.
Let me be your champion.
这份荣幸应该归我所有.
The honor should be mine.
看在我对您夫君敬爱有加的份上,
For the love I bore your Lord husband,
让我替他报仇罢.
let me avenge his death.
- 我愿为您而战, 夫人. - 这将是我的荣幸.
- I'll fight for you, My Lady. - It'll be my honor.
- 这将是我的荣幸. - 让这坏蛋飞!
- The honor should be mine. - Make the bad man fly!
瓦狄斯爵士...
Ser Vardis...
你怎么不说话.
You're quiet.
你不想为我丈夫报仇吗?
Don't you want to avenge my husband?
我全心全意爱戴他, 夫人.
With all my heart, My Lady.
但这小恶魔只有我一半高.
But the Imp is half my size.
把宰杀这种人称作主持正义是可耻的.
It would be shameful to slaughter such a man and call it justice.
同意.
Agreed.
是你要求比武审判的.
You demanded a trial by combat.
我要找一位代理骑士. 我和你一样有此权利.
Now I demand a champion. I have that right, same as you.
夫人,
My Lady,
我很乐意为您与小恶魔的代理骑士决斗.
I will gladly fight the Imp's champion for you.
我也非常乐意, 爵士.
I wouldn't be too glad, Ser.
我选择我的兄弟詹姆.
I name my brother Jaime Lannister.
弑君者
The Kingslayer
离这儿有好几百里地.
is hundreds of miles from here.
送只渡鸦给他. 我很乐意等.
Send a raven for him. I'm happy to wait.
今天就必须审判.
The trial will be today.
有人愿意代表我吗?
Do I have a volunteer?
有人吗?
Anyone?
我想肯定没人愿意...
I think we can assume that no one is willing...
我代表侏儒上场吧.
I'll stand for the dwarf.
再喝口酒吧, 陛下?
More wine, Your Grace?
- 我刚才说到哪儿了? - 更单纯的时光.
- What was I saying? - Renly: Simpler time.
是的! 是的. 你年纪太小不记得了.
It was! It was. You're too young to remember.
是不是更单纯, 塞尔弥?
Wasn't it simpler, Selmy?
- 是的, 陛下. - 敌人都在明处,
- It was, Your Grace. - The enemy was right  in the open,
虽然很邪恶, 但是绝对开诚布公.
vicious as you like, all but sending you a bloody invitation.
一点也不象现在.
Nothing like today.
- 听起来很令人兴奋. - 令人兴奋, 是的.
- It sounds exhilarating. - Exhilarating, yes.
也许不如那些舞会
Not as exhilarating as those balls
你喜欢的化妆舞会.
and masquerades you like to throw.
你上过河间地的姑娘吗?
You ever fuck a Riverlands girl?
有一次. 我想.
Once. I think.
你想? 我想你应该记得.
You think? I think you'd remember.
我们那时候, 如果你没有...
Back in our day, you weren't a real man
上全七国每一国的姑娘就不能算是真男人
until you'd fucked one girl from each of the Seven Kingdoms
另外还要加上河间地的.
and the Riverlands.
- 我们称之为 "满八." - 那真是些幸运的姑娘.
- We used to call it "making the eight." - Those were some lucky girls.
你完成过满八吗, 巴利斯坦?
You ever make the eight, Barristan?
我想没有, 陛下.
I don't believe so, Your Grace.
那真是些好日子.
Those were the days.
你是说什么日子?
Which days, exactly?
是半个维斯特洛打另半个, 死了成千上万人的日子?
The ones where half of Westeros fought the other half and millions died?
还是在那之前, 疯王屠杀妇女和婴儿的日子
Or before that, when the Mad King slaughtered women and babies
只因他头脑里有个声音要他这样做?
because the voices in his head told him they deserved it?
还是更早之前, 恶龙将城市烧成白地的日子?
Or way before that, when dragons burned whole cities to the ground?
别紧张, 小子.
Easy, boy.
你是我的兄弟, 但你也是在对国王说话.
You might be my brother, but you're speaking to the King.
我想那确实算是英雄壮举...
I suppose it was all rather heroic...
当你喝醉酒后找个可怜的河间地女人
If you were drunk enough and had some poor Riverlands whore
放进你那话儿并完成所谓的满八.
to shove your prick inside and make the eight.
再喝口酒吧, 陛下?
More wine, Your Grace?
他们几乎烧掉了河间地的所有东西:
They burned most everything in the Riverlands:
我们的田地; 我们的粮仓;
Our fields; Our granaries;
我们的家.
our homes.
他们抢走我们的女人, 强奸她们.
They took our women, then they took 'em again.
然后还把她们杀死
When they was done, they butchered them
就象是杀死牲畜.
as if they was animals.
他们在我们的孩子身上
They covered our children
浇柏油
in pitch
然后放火烧.
and lit them on fire.
最大的可能是土匪.
Brigands, most likely.
他们不是毛贼.
They weren't thieves.
他们并不偷东西.
They didn't steal nothing.
他们甚至扔了点东西, 陛下.
They even left something behind, Your Grace.
你们面前的是国王之手, 不是国王.
It's the King's Hand you're addressing, not the King.
国王去打猎了.
The King is hunting.
鱼. 徒利家族的标志.
Fish. The Sigil of House Tully.
那是您夫人的家族吧... 徒利, 首相大人?
Isn't that your wife's house... Tully, My Lord Hand?
那些人佩戴什么纹章?
These men, were they flying a Sigil?
- 打什么旗帜? - 没有, 陛...
- A banner? - None, your...
首相.
Hand.
领头的那个人...
The one who was leading them...
比我见过最高的人还高一尺,
Taller by a foot than any man I've ever met,
我亲眼见他把我们的铁匠砍成两半,
saw him cut the blacksmith in two,
还亲眼见他砍掉一匹马的头
saw him take the head off a horse
只用他的剑挥了一下.
with a single swing of his sword.
听着象我们认识的某个人.
That sounds like someone we know.
魔山.
The Mountain.
你说的是格雷果克里冈爵士.
You're describing Ser Gregor Clegane.
格雷果爵士怎么会成土匪?
Why should Ser Gregor turn brigand?
他是个受封的骑士.
The man is an anointed knight.
我听说他被称为泰温兰尼斯特的疯狗.
I've heard him called Tywin Lannister's mad dog.
我相信你也听说过.
I'm sure you have as well.
您知道为什么
Can you think of any reason
兰尼斯特家的人
the Lannisters might possibly have
对您夫人有这么大的火气吗?
for being angry with your wife?
如果真是兰尼斯特家
Maester Pycelle: If the Lannisters
下令攻击
were to order attacks on villages
受国王保护的村庄,
under the King's protection,
- 那将... - 那将等于是
- it would be... - That would be almost as brazen
公然在都城的大街上攻击国王之手.
as attacking the Hand of the King in the streets of the capital.
嗯...
Well...
我无法归还你们的家园
I cannot give you back your homes
更不能将死者复生,
or restore your dead to life,
但或许我能还你们一个公道
but perhaps I can give you justice
以我们的国王劳勃之名.
in the name of our King, Robert.
贝里唐德利恩大人.
Lord Beric Dondarrion.
你立刻率领一百名士兵
You shall have the command. Assemble 100 men
- 驰往格雷果爵士的城堡. - 遵命.
- and ride to Ser Gregor's keep. - As you command.
以拜拉席德家族的,
In the name of Robert of the House Baratheon,
劳勃一世,
the first of his name,
安达尔人与先民的国王, 七国统治者
King of the Andals and the first men, Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
暨全境守护者之名,
and protector of the realm,
我命令你实施国王的正义
I charge you to bring the King's Justice
处置虚伪的骑士格雷果克里冈
to the false knight Gregor Clegane
以及所有与他合谋的共犯.
and all those who shared in his crimes.
谴责其恶行
I denounce him
取消其权利.
and attaint him.
褫夺其一切官阶及头衔,
I strip him of all ranks and titles,
一切封地及财产,
of all lands and holdings,
- 并判处其死刑. - 大人...
- and sentence him to death. - My Lord...
这... 这是一项重大的举措.
This... this is a drastic action.
最好先等劳勃国王回来.
It would be better to wait for King Robert's return.
- 派席尔大学士. - 大人.
- Grand Maester Pycelle. - My Lord.
送一只渡鸦去凯岩城.
Send a raven to Casterly Rock.
通知泰温兰尼斯特前来宫廷
Inform Tywin Lannister that he has been summoned to court
对其封臣的罪行作出解释.
to answer for the crimes of his bannermen.
他必须在两周内赶到, 否则将被视为王室的敌人
He will arrive within the fortnight or be branded an enemy of the crown
国家的叛徒.
and a traitor to the realm.
真是英勇的举动, 大人, 令人赞赏.
A bold move, My Lord, and admirable.
但是拉扯狮子尾巴是否明智呢?
But is it wise to yank the lion's tail?
泰温兰尼斯特是七国上下最富有的人.
Tywin Lannister is the richest man in all the Seven Kingdoms.
战争是靠黄金而非士兵打赢的.
Gold wins wars, not soldiers.
那为什么是劳勃成为国王
Then how come Robert is King
而非泰温兰尼斯特呢?
and not Tywin Lannister?
坚持住!
Hold!
- 进攻, 进攻! - 快点, 瓦狄斯爵士!
- Attack attack! - Come on, Ser Vardis!
进攻!
Attack!
站住了打, 懦夫!
Stand and fight, coward!
是的!
Yes!
够了, 瓦狄斯爵士! 快收拾他.
Enough, Ser Vardis! Finish him.
你怎么了? 站起来!
What are you doing? Get up!
站起来, 站起来, 站起来!
Get up, get up, get up!
快举剑. 举剑!
Raise your sword. Raise it!
起来, 兄弟!
Get up, man!
- 快站起来! - 起来!
- On your feet! - Get up!
起来战斗, 瓦狄斯爵士!
Get up and fight, Ser Vardis!
不! 饶他一命!
No! Have mercy!
结束了?
Is it over?
你的打法没有荣誉可言!
You don't fight with honor!
没有.
No.
他有荣誉.
He did.
现在我可以看那小坏蛋飞了吗?
Can I make the little man fly now?
这个小坏蛋可不会飞.
Not this little man.
这个小坏蛋要回家了.
This little man is going home.
我想你拿了我的东西.
I believe you have something of mine.
兰尼斯特有债必还.
A Lannister always pays his debts.
现在你的头发梳得真象一个南方淑女.
You wear your hair like a real southern lady now.
嗯, 为什么不呢? 我们现在是在南方呀.
Well, why shouldn't I? We're in the South.
记得你来自哪里是很重要的.
It's important to remember where you come from.
我不确定你母亲是否会喜欢这些新发型.
I'm not sure your mother would like these new styles.
我母亲也不是来自北境.
My mother isn't from the North.
我知道这一点.
I'm aware of that.
你为什么关心这个?
Why do you care?
你自己有头发吗?
Do you even have hair under there?
是的. 我有头发.
Yes. I have hair.
我从没看到过.
I've never seen it.
你想看吗?
Would you like to?
不.
No.
你是来自哪里呢? 南方还是北方?
Where are you from anyway? The North or the South?
我来自一个很小的村庄, 是在...
I come from a very small village in...
哦, 等等.
Oh, wait.
我刚发现我不关心这个.
I just realized I don't care.
- 珊莎... - 修女.
- Sansa... - Septa.
现在你变粗鲁了.
Now you are being rude.
王子.
My prince.
小姐.
My Lady.
我恐怕表现得有些粗暴
I fear I have behaved monstrously
在过去的几周里.
the past few weeks.
可以吗?
With your permission?
它很漂亮,
It's beautiful,
很象你母亲戴的那个.
like the one your mother wears.
有朝一日你将成为王后.
You'll be queen someday.
你必须打扮得象个王后.
It's only fitting you should look the part.
你能原谅我的粗鲁吗?
Will you forgive me for my rudeness?
没什么要原谅的.
There's nothing to forgive.
你是我亲爱的小姐.
You're My Lady.
有朝一日我们会在朝堂上举行婚礼.
One day we'll be married in the throne room.
七国各地的领主和夫人们都会赶来,
Lords and ladies from all over the Seven Kingdoms will come,
从最北端城堡
from the last hearth in the North
到最南端的海滨,
to the Salt Shore in the South,
你将是他们最高贵的王后.
and you will be Queen over all of them.
我永远不会再对你无礼.
I'll never disrespect you again.
我也永远不会再对你粗暴.
I'll never be cruel to you again.
你明白吗?
Do you understand me?
你是我亲爱的小姐,
You're My Lady now,
从今天开始
from this day
直到我生命的最后一天.
until my last day.
停下.
Stop.
- 停下! - 哦哇.
- Stop! - Whoa.
- 你在干什么? - 去君临.
- What are you doing? - Going to King's Landing.
乘一辆运芜菁的车子?
In a turnip cart?
我会在白港找一条去南方的船.
I'll find a ship heading south in White Harbor.
你付得起船钱吗?
And you can afford that?
我的一些朋友比另一些慷慨.
Some of my friends are more generous than others.
君临有上千象你这样的姑娘.
There's a thousand girls like you in King's Landing.
那我会有很多同伴.
So I'll have lots of company.
是的, 你会很受欢迎...
Yes, you'll be very popular...
直到哪一天某个肥胖的领主光临
Until some fat lord comes to visit
肚子很大而那话儿很小
with a big belly and a little prick
因为你伺候得他不满意, 把你打得满地找牙.
and he can't get it up so he knocks all your teeth out.
我留在这里会怎样?
And what will happen to me if I stay here?
我会成为葛雷乔伊夫人吗,
Will I become Lady Greyjoy,
- 会成为铁群岛的女主人吗? - 别傻了.
- mistress of the Iron Islands? - Don't be a fool.
我听说詹姆兰尼斯特攻击了史塔克大人
I hear Jaime Lannister attacked Lord Stark
就在君临城的大街上.
in the streets of King's Landing.
很快方圆百里的所有男人都将从军南下
Every man for a hundred miles will be marching off to war soon
他们多数永远都不会再回来.
and most of them will never come back.
这儿没我什么事了.
There's nothing left for me here.
我们走吧, 斯特芬.
Let's go, Stefon.
走喽.
Giddyup.
让我再看一眼!
Let me see it one more time!
看什么?
See what?
我会想念你的.
I'm going to miss you.
我知道.
I know.
我要送你们俩回临冬城.
I'm sending you both back to Winterfell.
- 什么?! - 听我说...
- What?! - Listen...
- 乔佛里的事怎么办? - 因为你的腿伤好不了吗?
- What about Joffrey? - Are you dying because of your leg?
所以你要送我们回家?
Is that why you're sending us home?
什么? 不是.
What? No.
求你了, 父亲. 不要.
Please, father. Please don't.
不可以. 我要跟西利欧上课.
You can't. I've got my lessons with Syrio.
我一定会表现好的.
I'm finally getting good.
这不是在惩罚你们.
This isn't a punishment.
我让你们回临冬城是为你们的安全着想.
I want you back in Winterfell for your own safety.
我们可以带西利欧一起走吗?
Can we take Syrio back with us?
谁管你的笨舞蹈老师啊?
Who cares about your stupid dancing teacher?
我不能走.
I can't go.
我是要嫁给乔佛里王子的.
I'm supposed to marry Prince Joffrey.
我爱他, 我要做他的王后
I love him and I'm meant to be his Queen
- 为他生孩子. - 七层地狱啊.
- and have his babies. - Seven hells.
等你再大点,
When you're old enough,
我会给你找个配得上你的人,
I'll make you a match with someone who's worthy of you,
既勇敢又温柔又强壮...
someone who's brave and gentle and strong...
我不要什么勇敢温柔又强壮的人. 我只要他!
I don't want someone brave and gentle and strong. I want him!
他会成为最伟大的国王, 如同黄金雄狮,
He'll be the greatest King that ever was, a golden lion,
我会为她生下拥有漂亮金发的儿女.
and I'll give him sons with beautiful blond hair.
他才不是狮子, 白痴.
The lion'sot s Sigil, idiot.
他是鹿, 象他父亲一样.
He's a stag, like his father.
他才不是. 他一点也不象那个酒鬼国王.
He is not. He's nothing like that old drunk King.
去吧, 孩子们. 让修女帮你们收拾东西.
Go on, girls. Get your Septa and start packing your things.
- 等等! - 来吧.
- Wait! - Come on.
但这不公平!
But it's not fair!
"欧瑞斯拜拉席恩, 黑发."
"Lord Orys Baratheon, black of hair."
"阿克谢尔拜拉席恩, 黑发."
"Axel Baratheon, black of hair."
"莱昂内尔拜拉席恩, 黑发."
"Lyonel Baratheon, black of hair."
"斯蒂芬拜拉席恩, 黑发."
"Steffon Baratheon, black of hair."
"劳勃拜拉席恩, 黑发."
"Robert Baratheon, black of hair."
"乔佛里拜拉席恩...
"Joffrey Baratheon...
金发."
Golden-haired."
丹妮莉丝!
Daenerys!
我妹妹在哪儿?
Where's my sister?
拦住他.
Stop him.
她在哪儿?
Where is she?
嗯?
Hmm?
她在哪儿? 我来参加宴会.
Where is she? I'm here for the feast.
- 那烂女人的宴会? - 来.
- The whore's feast? - Come.
把你的手拿开!
Get your hands off me!
谁也不能触碰真龙!
No one touches the Dragon!
(酸腿国王!)
Khal rhae mhar!
(他来了!)
Me ifa!
卓戈卡奥!
Khal Drogo!
我是来参加宴会的.
I'm here for the feast.
(你的位子在那儿.)
Nevakhi vekha ha maan.
卓戈卡奥说你的座位在那里.
Khal Drogo says there is a place for you.
那个地方.
Back there.
那不是给国王坐的地方.
That is no place for a King.
你不是国王.
You are no King.
离我远点!
Keep away from me!
韦赛里斯, 求你了.
Viserys, please.
原来她在这儿.
There she is.
把剑收起来. 这会把我们全害死的.
Put the sword down. They'll kill us all.
他们奈何不了我们.
They can't kill us.
他们不能在他们的圣城里流血.
They can't shed blood in their sacred city.
但我能.
But I can.
我只想要属于我的东西.
I want what I came for.
我只想要他答应我的那顶王冠.
I want the crown he promised me.
他买了你.
He bought you.
但他从未付钱.
But he never paid for you.
告诉他我要完成交易, 否则我就要收回你.
Tell him I want what was bargained for or I'm taking you back.
他可以留下孩子.
He can keep the baby.
我会把它割下来给他.
I'll cut it out and leave it for him.
(......)
Anha vazhak maan rek me zala.
Anha vazhak maan firikhnharen hoshora
(......)
ma mahrazhi aqovi affin mori atihi mae!
他说什么?
What's he saying?
他说好的.
He says yes.
你将拥有一顶黄金王冠...
You shall have a golden crown...
任谁看了都会颤抖.
That men shall tremble to behold.
我要的就只是这个.
That was all I wanted.
他答应要给我的.
What-what was promised.
(抓住他.)
Qora mae.
不!
No!
不! 你们不准碰我.
No! You cannot touch me.
我是真龙. 我是真龙!
I am the Dragon. I am the Dragon!
我要我的王冠! 啊!
I want my crown! Ahh!
(拿锅来!)
Ammeni haz jolin!
- 请你转过头, 卡丽熙. - 不.
- Look away, Khaleesi. - No.
不, 丹妮.
No, dany.
丹妮, 告诉他们.
Dany, tell them.
告诉他们!
Make them!
丹妮, 让他们...
Dany, make them...
不, 你不能!
No, you can't!
只要... 求你了!
Just... please!
丹妮, 求你了!
Dany, please!
国王的王冠.
A crown for a King.
卡丽熙?
Khaleesi?
他不是真龙.
He was no Dragon.
真龙不怕火.
Fire cannot kill a Dragon.
= 翻译: freesand =
== sync, corrected by elderman ==